<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jannik Buhr on jmbuhr.de</title>
    <link>https://jmbuhr.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jannik Buhr on jmbuhr.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;#169; 2021 Jannik Buhr</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 09:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jmbuhr.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to data analysis with R WS21</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/dataintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/dataintro/</guid>
      <description>Sign up for biochemists at Heidelberg University: https://jmbuhr.de/dataintro/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why the Dunning-Krueger Effect is Probably Not Real</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2021-03-20-why-the-dunning-krueger-effect-is-probably-not-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2021-03-20-why-the-dunning-krueger-effect-is-probably-not-real/</guid>
      <description>The Dunning-Krueger Effect is Probably Not Real   I recently came across this article by Jonathan Jarry (“The Dunning-Kruger Effect Is Probably Not Real” n.d.).
I am not going to try and steal his thunder, so please do go ahead and read the article. It is well written, thoroughly researched and presents a valid point. Everything points towards the Dunning-Krueger effect being largely just an artifact of the way the original authors analyzed their data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to git and GitHub</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/gitintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/gitintro/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Darkmode for your distill site</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2021-03-14-making-a-darkmode-for-your-distill-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2021-03-14-making-a-darkmode-for-your-distill-site/</guid>
      <description>Join the Dark Side!   &amp;hellip; we have cookies.
There are many motivations to adding a dark mode to your site. I just like it, when things look consistent. So I also want my site to reflect that. But because at the same time I am also not very good at making things look consistent, which is why I mostly outsource design choices as much as I can. Here, for example, this means that I took the color values for the dark theme from the amazing nord color palette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to data analysis with R (Online)</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/dataintro20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/dataintro20/</guid>
      <description>Greetings Adventurers,
And welcome to the next iteration of my introductory R course for data visualization and analysis. Because the concepts you will learn in this course will be most useful in areas where the working language is English, this course will also be in English. But feel free to ask questions in German as well any time. Let us start with the formalities.
Sign up     In order for us to stay connected during the course, please send me an email via my contact form and mention your name, as well as the course you are referring to (bachelor, master).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to data analysis with R</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/dataintro19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/teaching/dataintro19/</guid>
      <description>This course is available in English (master students) and German (bachelor students).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The father</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2020-10-26-12-the-father/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2020-10-26-12-the-father/</guid>
      <description>Teaser   The Father (by Florian Zeller) tells the story of a father-daughter relationship, put under strain by the increasing dementia of the father. The story is told from the perspective of the father, André, and allows the audience to see the world through his perspective - with all the disjunctures, confusion and distress that dementia causes.
The production is co-directed by Dennis Massmann and Timothy Williams (previously &amp;lsquo;Twelve Angry Men&amp;rsquo;) and integrates this modern dramatic farce with elements of physical theatre to transport the audience into the mind of André.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Angry Men</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2020-10-26-12-angry-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2020-10-26-12-angry-men/</guid>
      <description>Teaser   A young man is accused of having killed his father, the evidence points in this direction, the witnesses corroborate the story against him. His fate rests in the hand of a jury - twelve men and women to decide if he should be executed. Eleven jurors are certain he is the murderer, but for one some questions remain open. This Anglistic Seminar performance approaches a modern classic from a fresh perspective, drawing the audience into the moral conundrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender3d School Open Movie</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2021-01-09-blenderschoolopenmovie2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2021-01-09-blenderschoolopenmovie2019/</guid>
      <description>At the end of the Summer 2019 we got together as a group that met at the blender3d Summer School, a yearly event with blender workshops, to produce a short movie within 2 weeks. This is the result:
  You can learn more about it on the project website. I was very lucky to work with such talented and inspirational people and am proud of what we achieved in such a small amount of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>demonstration</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2020-02-15-demonstration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/2020-02-15-demonstration/</guid>
      <description>Tests   Citations     R Core Team (2020)
Math     Example from the mathjax demo:
When \(a \ne 0\), there are two solutions to \(ax^2 + bx + c = 0\) and they are $$x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}.$$
If I have a random $ and another $ in my text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>demonstration 2</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>Rendering mathematical equations     Examples from the mathjax demo:
Rmarkdown     In .Rmarkdown documents, you can use either
$a \ne 0$ to get inline math: \(a \ne 0\). There is no conflict with using dollar symbols regularly, because knitr automatically escapes freestanding dollar symbols.
And you can use
$x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}.$$ to get a math paragraph:
$$x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impressum</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/impressum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/impressum/</guid>
      <description>Jannik Buhr
Da-Vinci Str. 17
69115 Heidelberg
E-Mail: jannik [punkt] buhr [at] gmail [punkt] com
Haftungsausschluss     Haftung für Inhalte     Als Diensteanbieter sind wir gemäß § 7 Abs.1 TMG für eigene Inhalte auf diesen Seiten nach den allgemeinen Gesetzen verantwortlich. Nach §§ 8 bis 10 TMG sind wir als Diensteanbieter jedoch nicht verpflichtet, übermittelte oder gespeicherte fremde Informationen zu überwachen oder nach Umständen zu forschen, die auf eine rechtswidrige Tätigkeit hinweisen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks!</title>
      <link>https://jmbuhr.de/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jmbuhr.de/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to the hugo-apero theme:
   Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
   Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
   Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
